Yiyu Chen

Full Stack Software Developer

Email: yiyuchen9@gmail.com

Mobile: 022 189 6739

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yiyuchen-nz/

Github: https://github.com/yiyuchen-nz

Career Objective

I am looking for software developer roles. I am a curious and self-motivated software developer. I bring with me 3 years experience of teaching and 1 year experience of customer service to my new career in tech. What I learned about myself in my previous roles was that I can stay calm and work well under pressure. I also demonstrated communication, problem-solving and teamwork skills.

During training in Dev Academy, as soon as my first web page showing on the browser, I was amazed by the power of code. I am excited that I can make things for many other people to use. I am so glad I took the lead to tech and curious to learn new technologies.

Skills

Web Deve	lopment
----------	---------

- Used HTML and CSS to build a responsive personal blog and for multiple team based projects
- Have experience with server-side framework: Node.js,
 Express.js and client-side tools React.js and Redux Toolkit

Programming language

 JavaScript is the main language I am using. I have experience in functional programming and asynchronous programming by completing dozens of solo and pairprogramming challenges, kata and group projects.

Source Control

 Used Git to track and manage changes to code for solo programming and to collaborate with other developers for group projects

Fast learner

 Learned about object-oriented programming and Phaser 3 within 7 days to build a 2D shooting game for the final group project in Dev Academy

Other Skills

- I can speak English, Mandarin, Cantonese
- My personal skills are communication, teamwork, leadership, problem solving

Experience

Student/Apprentice - Web Development Bootcamp

Dev Academy Aotearoa, Auckland, NewZealand 04/2022 - 07/2022

- This was a 15 week full immersion software development bootcamp that mimics a real-life development team as closely as possible. The course taught us a modern web dev stack with a strong emphasis on human skills, empathy, collaboration, and working in teams using agile methodology.
- For my final project, I took on a new challenge to build a game with the team. We worked under the stress of learning new tech and deadline. We learned about Phaser3 and Object Oriented programming within 7 days. My role was the product owner. I demonstrated leadership and conflict solving skills by making final decisions to the product when different opinions appeared in the team.

Sales Asistant

Farmers Takapuna store, Auckland, NewZealand 03/2020 - present

- My main responsibilities are demonstrating the proper use of a variety of beauty, hair, and skin care product and identifying client needs and goals, and assisting them in finding and selecting appropriate products, selling products to clients when appropriate
- I demonstrate customer service, communication and active listening skills, and the ability to work well with others.

IELTS Teacher

Self-employed, online lessons based in Auckland 04/2019-04/2021

- I delivered online 1-on-1 IELTS lessons to students age ranging from high school students to university students. I needed to manage and track the performance of students, and provide verbal or written feedback after each lesson.
- As self-employed, it was important to be constantly self motivated and to have the ability to work independently. I also demonstrated good social media knowledge by recruiting students through online social media platform.

New Oriental Education Group, Dongguan, China 03/2018 - 04/2019

- I conducted well structured classes to students and managed a class of up to 16 students. My other responsibilities include: making teaching plans, marking and providing students with written feedbacks, maintaining relationships with students' parents
- The main skills that I used and gained from this role were leadership, student engagement, public speaking, planning, and teamwork skills.

Education

Web Development (Training Scheme)

Dev Academy Aotearoa, Auckland, New Zealand 4/2022-7/2022

Full Stack Web Development

Postgraduate Diploma in International Hospitality Management

AUT, Auckland, New Zealand

2/2016-12/2016

Major in International Hospitality Management

Hobbies & Interests

Travelling, hiking, reading, boardgames, mindfulness

References Available on Request